<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Override language="English" nowhitespace="false" translatedname="Low gothic">
  <!-- Items -->
  <Entitydescription.medkit>Medkit assembled for field use, containing painkillers, broad-spectrum antibiotics, desinfectant, and biogel to treat a wide variety of injuries. Treats damage, burns, bleeding, and pain, with a minor amount of bloodloss restored.</Entitydescription.medkit>

  <!-- Afflictions -->
  <Afflictiondescription.omnibless>Your faith in the Omnissiah has been rewarded, granting you increased repair speed, attack damage, skill gain speed, structure repair speed, and move speed.</Afflictiondescription.omnibless>

  <!-- Talent afflictions -->
  <afflictionname.skedaddle>Skedaddle</afflictionname.skedaddle>
  <afflictiondescription.skedaddle>The subject is skedaddling away!</afflictiondescription.skedaddle>

  <!-- Jobs -->
  <Jobdescription.skitari>The Skitarii (sing. Skitarius), also known as the Tech-Guard and the Legiones Skitarii, are the cybernetic military forces of the Adeptus Mechanicus of the Imperium of Man.</Jobdescription.skitari>
  <Jobdescription.magos>A magos (pronounced MAY-gohs) (pl. magi) is a Tech-priest who is a recognised master of a technological or scientific discipline, having devoted many standard years of service to the Omnissiah in that area of study.</Jobdescription.magos>
  <Jobdescription.engineseer>Enginseers are perhaps the most common of the Tech-priests of the Adeptus Mechanicus. They view themselves as engineer-mystics dedicated to the Omnissiah, and each Enginseer possesses a wealth of knowledge on how to maintain and repair mechanical and electronic technology.</Jobdescription.engineseer>

  <!-- Talents -->
  <talentname.skedaddle>Skedaddle</talentname.skedaddle>
  <talentdescription.skedaddle>Move [value]% faster. When you are attacked, this bonus is increased to [attackedvalue]% for [seconds] seconds.</talentdescription.skedaddle>
  <talentname.crewlayabout>Crew Layabout</talentname.crewlayabout>
  <talentdescription.crewlayabout>Allies near you repair [repairspeed]% faster and gain a bonus of [amount] to all skills.</talentdescription.crewlayabout>
  <afflictionname.pickinguptheslack>Picking Up the Slack</afflictionname.pickinguptheslack>
  <afflictiondescription.pickinguptheslack>The subject feels they must work a bit harder to make up for someone else.</afflictiondescription.pickinguptheslack>
  <talentname.recipeset1>Lasgun and Power Cell Templates</talentname.recipeset1>
  <talentname.recipeset2>Boltor Templates</talentname.recipeset2>
  <talentname.recipeset3>Plasma Templates</talentname.recipeset3>

  <!-- Genetics -->
  <Entityname.implant1>Secondary Heart</Entityname.implant1>
  <Entitydescription.implant1>Phase 1: This simplest and most self-sufficient of implants allows a Space Marine to survive his other heart being damaged or destroyed, and to survive in low oxygen environments. Not just a back-up, the secondary heart can boost the blood flow around the Marine's body.</Entitydescription.implant1>
  <Entityname.implant2>Ossmodula</Entityname.implant2>
  <Entitydescription.implant2>Phase 2: A small, complex, tubular organ, the ossmodula secretes hormones that both affect the ossification of the skeleton and encourages the forming bone growths to absorb ceramic-based chemicals that are laced into the Marine's diet. This drastically alters the way a Space Marine's bones grow and develop. Two years after this implant is first put in the subject's long bones will have increased in size and strength (along with most other bones), and the rib cage will have been fused into a solid, bulletproof mass of interlocking plates. It is not clear how a Space Marine's (non-implanted) lungs operate without a rib cage that can expand and contract.</Entitydescription.implant2>
  <Entityname.implant3>Biscopea</Entityname.implant3>
  <Entitydescription.implant3>Phase 3: This small, circular organ is inserted into the chest cavity and releases hormones that vastly increase muscle growth throughout the marine's body. It also serves to form the hormonal basis for many of the later implants.</Entitydescription.implant3>
  <Entityname.implant4>Haemastamen</Entityname.implant4>
  <Entitydescription.implant4>Phase 4: Implanted into the main circulatory system, this tiny implant not only increases the haemoglobin content of the subject's blood, making it more efficient at carrying oxygen around the body and making the subject's blood a bright red, it also serves to monitor and control the actions of the phase 2 and phase 3 implants.</Entitydescription.implant4>
  <Entityname.implant5>Larraman's Organ</Entityname.implant5>
  <Entitydescription.implant5>Phase 5: A liver-shaped organ about the size of a golf-ball, this implant is placed within the chest cavity and connected to the circulatory system. It generates and controls 'Larraman cells', which are released into the blood stream if the recipient is wounded. They attach themselves to leukocytes (white blood cells) in the blood and are carried to the site of the wound, whereupon contact with air they form a near instant patch of scar tissue, sealing any wounds the Space Marine may suffer - acting like platelets, only better.</Entitydescription.implant5>
  <Entityname.implant6>Catalepsean Node</Entityname.implant6>
  <Entitydescription.implant6>Phase 6: Implanted into the back of the brain, this pea-sized organ influences the circadian rhythms of sleep and the body's response to sleep deprivation. If deprived of sleep, the catalepsean node cuts in. The node allows a Marine to sleep and remain awake at the same time by switching off areas of his brain sequentially. This process cannot replace sleep entirely, but increases the Marine's survivability by allowing perception of the environment while resting. This means that a Space Marine needs no more than 4 hours of sleep a day, and can potentially go for 2 weeks without any sleep at all.</Entitydescription.implant6>
  <Entityname.implant7>Preomnor</Entityname.implant7>
  <Entitydescription.implant7>Phase 7: This is essentially a pre-stomach that can neutralise otherwise poisonous or indigestible foods. No actual digestion takes place in the preomnor, as it acts as a decontamination chamber placed before the natural stomach in the body's system and can be isolated from the rest of the digestive tract in order to contain particularly troublesome intake.</Entitydescription.implant7>
  <Entityname.implant8>Omophagea</Entityname.implant8>
  <Entitydescription.implant8>Phase 8: This implant, also called "the Remembrancer", allows a Space Marine to 'learn by eating'. It is situated in the spinal cord but is actually part of the brain. Four nerve bundles are implanted connecting the spine and the stomach wall. Able to 'read' or absorb genetic material consumed by the marine, the omophagea transmits the gained information to the Marine's brain as a set of memories or experiences. It is the presence of this organ which has led to the various flesh-eating and blood-drinking rituals for which the Astartes are famous, as well as giving names to chapters such as the Blood Drinkers and Flesh Tearers. Over time, mutations in this implant have given some chapters unnatural cravings for blood or flesh.</Entitydescription.implant8>
  <Entityname.implant9>Multi-lung</Entityname.implant9>
  <Entitydescription.implant9>Phase 9: This additional lung activates when a Space Marine needs to breathe in low-oxygen or poisoned atmospheres, and even water. The natural lungs are closed off by a sphincter muscle associated with the multi-lung and the implanted organ takes over breathing operations. It has highly efficient toxin dispersal systems.</Entitydescription.implant9>
  <Entityname.implant10>Occulobe</Entityname.implant10>
  <Entitydescription.implant10>Phase 10: This implant sits at the base of the brain, and provides hormonal and genetic stimuli which enable a Marine's eyes to respond to optic-therapy. This in turn allows the Apothecaries to make adjustments to the growth patterns of the eye and the light-receptive retinal cells - the result being that Space Marines have far superior vision to normal humans, and can see in low-light conditions almost as well as in daylight.</Entitydescription.implant10>
  <Entityname.implant11>Lyman's Ear</Entityname.implant11>
  <Entitydescription.implant11>Phase 11: Not only does this implant make a Space Marine immune to dizziness or motion sickness, it also allows Space Marines to consciously filter out and enhance certain sounds. The Lyman's Ear completely replaces a Marine's original ears. It is externally indistinguishable from a normal human ear.</Entitydescription.implant11>
  <Entityname.implant12>Sus-an Membrane</Entityname.implant12>
  <Entitydescription.implant12>Phase 12: Initially implanted above the brain, this membrane eventually merges with the recipient's entire brain. Ineffective without follow-up chemical therapy and training, with sufficient training a Space Marine can use this implant to enter a state of suspended animation, consciously or as an automatic reaction to extreme trauma, keeping the Marine alive for years, even if he has suffered otherwise mortal wounds. Only the appropriate chemical therapy or auto-suggestion can revive a Marine from this state. The longest recorded period spent in suspended animation was undertaken by Brother Silas Err of the Dark Angels, who was revived after 567 years (d.321.M37). This organ is also known as the hibernator implant.</Entitydescription.implant12>
  <Entityname.implant13>Melanchromic Organ</Entityname.implant13>
  <Entitydescription.implant13>Phase 13: This implant controls the amount of melanin in a Marine's skin. Exposure to high levels of sunlight will result in the Marine's skin darkening to compensate. It also protects the Marine from other forms of radiation.</Entitydescription.implant13>
  <Entityname.implant14>Oolitic Kidney</Entityname.implant14>
  <Entitydescription.implant14>Phase 14: In conjunction with the secondary heart this implant allows a Space Marine to filter his blood very quickly, rendering him immune to most poisons. This action comes at a price, however, as this emergency detoxification usually renders the Marine unconscious while his blood is circulated at high speed. The organ's everyday function is to monitor the entire circulatory system and allow other organs to function effectively.</Entitydescription.implant14>
  <Entityname.implant15>Neuroglottis</Entityname.implant15>
  <Entitydescription.implant15>Phase 15: This enhances a Space Marine's sense of taste to such a high degree that he can identify many common chemicals by taste alone. A Marine can even track a target by taste.</Entitydescription.implant15>
  <Entityname.implant16>Mucranoid</Entityname.implant16>
  <Entitydescription.implant16>Phase 16: This implant allows a Space Marine to sweat a substance that coats the skin and offers resistance to extreme heat and cold and can even provide some protection for the marine in a vacuum. This can only be activated by outside treatment, and is common when Space Marines are expected to be fighting in vacuum.</Entitydescription.implant16>
  <Entityname.implant17>Betcher's Gland</Entityname.implant17>
  <Entitydescription.implant17>Phase 17: Consists of two identical glands, implanted either into the lower lip, alongside the salivary glands, or into the hard palate. The gland works in a similar way to the poison gland of venomous reptiles by synthesizing and storing deadly poison, which the Marines themselves are immune to. This allows a Space Marine to spit a blinding contact poison. The poison is also corrosive and can even burn away "strong" metals, given sufficient time.</Entitydescription.implant17>
  <Entityname.implant18>Progenoids</Entityname.implant18>
  <Entitydescription.implant18>Phase 18: There are two of these glands, one situated in the neck and the other within the chest cavity. These glands are vitally important and represent the future of the Chapter, as the only way new gene-seed can be produced is by reproducing it within the bodies of the Marines themselves. This is the implant's only purpose. The glands absorb genetic material from the other implanted organs. When they have matured, each gland will have developed a single gene-seed corresponding to each of the zygotes which have been implanted into the Marine.</Entitydescription.implant18>
  <Entityname.blackcarapase>Black Carapace</Entityname.blackcarapase>
  <Entitydescription.blackcarapase>Phase 19: The most distinctive implant, it resembles a film of black plastic that is implanted directly beneath the skin of the Marine's torso in sheets. It hardens on the outside and sends invasive neural bundles into the Marine's body. After the organ has matured the recipient is then fitted with neural sensors and interface points cut into the carapace's surface. This allows a Space Marine to interface directly with his Power Armour. Without the Black Carapace many of the systems of the power armour will not function. While driving the vehicles of the Chapter, a special spinal interface plugged into the power armour and Black Carapace provides the Space Marine an intuitive 'feel' for vehicles systems and controls, literally making him a part of his vehicle. A similar cybernetic used by the Imperium of Man is the Mind Impulse Unit.</Entitydescription.blackcarapase>
  <Entityname.geneticmaterialastartes>Astartes Genetic Material: ([type])</Entityname.geneticmaterialastartes>
</Override>